绝命律师
第一季 第十集(季终)
翻译  西西  酸奶  joy_bwl  咯吱猫
翻译  寐兮  Liv  肉松  ellaxinxin
校对  喃喃
时间轴  梦龙  今  姜姜
后期  润包子小新  8T  虫虫不咬人
总监  喃喃
天呐
Jesus.
怎么可能成功
It can't be done.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
动了手脚吧
There's a trick?
肯定是
There's got to be.
如果没有动手脚
This guy wouldn't be putting any money
这人怎么会拿钱出来
on it unless there's a trick?
我说了  这不可能成功
I'm telling you -- it can't be done.
所以你放弃了
So you give up?
那好吧
Yeah, all right.
-等等  -没搞错吧
- Wait. What? - No way!
再来一次
Show me that again.
没问题  再出二十吧
Sure. You got another $20?
去你的
Screw this.
别生气啊
Don't go away mad.
你们想买劳力士表吗
Oh, hey, guys, you want to buy a Rolex?
等等
Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
那块冒牌表要卖多少钱
How much for that cheap piece of crap?
-看看是谁来了  -莫娜
- Look what the wind blew in. - Hey, Merna.
没搞错吧
Holy crap.
吉米  我就说你能脱罪
Jimmy, my man, I said you would beat the rap.
莫娜  给他倒杯酒
Hey, Merna, set him up, would you?
不了  莫娜  谢谢
Merna, no, thanks. I'm good.
给他满上  他其实想喝
No, go on. He don't mean it.
你刚刚出狱啊
You just got out of jail. Come on.
连酒都不喝一杯吗
You're, you're not gonna have a drink?
怎么可能啊
That'll be the day?
马可  别嚷了  我赶时间
Marco, settle down, okay? I'm in a rush.
我哥在外面的出租车里  计费表还跳着呢
My brother's outside in a taxi. The meter's running.
查克在外面
What, Chuck's outside?
让他别磨叽了
Tell him to pull that broomstick out of his ass
进来喝酒  我请客
and get in here. I'm buying.
不  我们没时间了  要赶飞机
No. No, no, we got no time. We're catching a plane.
我是来告别的
I came here to say goodbye.
我要搬去新墨西哥州的阿尔布开克
I'm moving to Albuquerque, New Mexico.
墨西哥  你要弃保潜逃吗
Mexico? You skipped bail?
是"新"墨西哥
New Mexico--
就是兔八哥和BB鸟在的那个地方
you know, like, uh, Bugs Bunny and the Road Runner, you know?
你要去那干什么
Yeah. What are you gonna do there?
在我哥的律所打杂  在收发室干活
I'm gonna work at his law firm, like, in the mailroom.
算是个新开始吧
It's a start, anyways.
你没搞错吧  老兄
What? N-now you're talking crazy, man.
你才出狱  就又想进去了
You just got out of jail. Now you want to go back?
给他工作等于坐牢啊
Because working for him, that's all that is.
马可  我别无他法了
Marco...I was done.
你懂吗  我没有逃脱制裁
You understand? I didn't beat the rap.
是查克赶来救了我
Chuck flew in and saved my ass.
是时候改变自己了
It's time to make some changes.
你可是"风流吉米"啊
Hey, listen, man. You're Slipping Jimmy.
你要改变什么
What do you got to change?
洗心革面  是时候长大了
Everything. It's time to grow up.
这又是谁说的  查克吗
Yeah, according to who, Chuck?
你也是一样  兄弟
The same goes for you, man.
你想一辈子都坐在这凳子上吗
You want to spend the rest of your life on that stool?
马可  看看你自己
I mean, come on, Marco. Look at yourself.
他在催我了  我得走了
All right, that's him. I got to hit it.
是啊  主人在召唤你呢
Geez. His master's voice.
-有必要吗  -你出去吧
- Really? - Look, come on. Go outside.
跟查克说你还有事忘了做
Tell Chuckles that you, you got some business you forgot.
-马可  -得了
- Marco. - Come on.
你好歹得干最后一票
Y-you got to have one last blowout.
我们再玩儿一次手表把戏
W-we'll do the watch thing again,
你之前说的那个...
but, but maybe we'll pull that--
那个骗钱圈套也不错
that tar-money scam you were talking about,
-约几个美女  -我答应他了
- get some girls... - I made a promise.
你是答应他了  但这是...
Yeah, you made a promise, but it was --
律师管这叫啥  受到胁迫
W-w-what do you might call it? Under duress.
他把你从监狱里捞了出来
Look, he got you out of jail, okay?
但他是你哥哥  他还能逼你不成
But he's your brother. I mean, what else is he gonna do?
马可  听我说
Marco, listen to me, all right?
不是查克逼我这么做的
Chuck's not making me do this.
他这是给我一个机会  我要抓住机会
He's giving me an opportunity, and I'm grabbing it.
就像迈尔斯·戴维斯放弃吹小号一样
Geez, it's like watching Miles Davis give up the trumpet.
著名音乐家
这是什么意思
What? What does that even mean?
简直是浪费你的天赋
It's just a waste, is all I'm saying.
我要飞去那里了
All right, look. I'm gonna fly out there.
等我安定下来  再打给你
I'm gonna get settled, and I'll call you. Yeah?
好吧  吉米
All right, Jimmy.
祝你一路平安
Hey, have a safe flight, all right?!
怎么了
What's up?
等着跟霍华德谈话
Just waiting to talk to Howard.
能问问谈什么吗
Can I ask about what?
我决定听你的
I'm taking your advice.
把案子给哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
I'm giving the case to HHM.
为什么
Why?
大概是因为
The fact that Chuck doesn't
查克不想让我在这里工作吧
want me here has something to do with it.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你为什么不早告诉我呢
Why didn't you just tell me?
我只是
I just...
我不想让你恨你哥哥
I didn't want you hating your own brother.
你是怎么发现的
How did you find out?
是金告诉你的吗
Did Kim tell you?
我自己弄明白了
I figured it out on my own.
也该弄明白了  对吧
It's about time, right?
我把矶鹞渡的文件拿来了
I brought the Sandpiper stuff with me.
就在我车里
It's down in my car.
你们可以主动扩大业务
I figure your guys could do the outreach.
如果那些老年人不想签你们
If any of those geezers don't want to sign with you,
把他们的名字给我
just give me their names.
我会劝他们签的
I'll talk them into it.
吉米  我真的不想让事情变成这个样子
You know, Jimmy, I never wanted it to go this way.
如果我说了算  我们至少会
If it had been up to me, we would have at least--
霍华德  我懂
Howard, I get it.
你哥哥对律所来说非常重要
Your brother's very important to the firm.
抱歉我当时说你是个混蛋
Sorry I called you a pigfucker.
我们还欠了你钱  不是吗
We owe you some money, don't we?
律师费  我记得是两万美金
The of-counsel fee -- I think we discussed $20,000.
再加上矶鹞渡一案的共同基金
That and whatever the common-fund proceeds
不管最终金额有多少
of Sandpiper ultimately adds up to,
你都会拿到两成
you'll receive 20% of that --
应该是一笔很可观的收入
Should be a very nice payday for you when it comes.
没错
Yep.
我还给你准备了些东西
I've got something for you, too.
是给查克准备的购物清单
Uh, it's a shopping list for Chuck.
他现在是好多了
I mean, he's doing better,
但他每天还是需要一些东西
but he still needs deliveries every day.
我觉得最好还是由别人来做
I think he'd be more comfortable with someone else doing it.
我知道了
I see.
你不需要亲自上门
You don't have to do it personally.
只要做好就行
It just needs to get done.
写得非常清楚了
It's pretty straightforward.
冰块倒是件麻烦事  但这是必需品
The ice is a pain in the ass, but he needs it.
我经常会溜进小旅馆里塞个一整包
I usually sneak into a motel and fill a garbage bag,
但你可以叫你的手下花钱买就好
but you can have whoever you hire just buy it.
最重要的是报纸
The most important thing is the newspapers.
《纽约时报》  还有《华尔街日报》
Uh, the New York Times, the Wall Street Journal --
这些都是必需品
They're a must.
尤班克那边有个报摊
There's a newsstand on Eubank
早上六点就有卖
that has both of them at 6:00 A.M.,
他习惯早起  所以一早给他比较好
which is good 'cause he's an early riser.
他订了《阿尔布开克日报》
The Albuquerque Journal he gets delivered,
但得有人把报纸带进屋
but somebody still has to bring it in for him.
你每天都做这些事吗
You've been doing all of this every day...
做了一年多吗
For over a year?
你会处理好这些事吗
You'll take care of this?
当然了
Absolutely.
肯定做得滴水不漏
I'll get it done and done right.
我一直很喜欢你  吉米
I always liked you, Jimmy.
记得吗
Remember?
我以前叫你"骗子查理"
I used to call you "Charlie Hustle."
我记得
Yeah, I remember that.
对不起  之前冲你大喊大叫
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
抱抱你真不错
That was nice.
你确定你没事吗
You sure you're all right?
发泄出来吧  没事的
It's not a crime to let it out.
没什么好发泄的  查克脑子有病
There's nothing to let out. Chuck's a sick man.
那不是借口
That's no excuse.
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
他觉得我是个混球
He thinks I'm a scumbag.
我没法让他改变看法
There's nothing I can do to change that.
我还能说什么
What else is there to say?
你真是太成熟了
Wow. That's mature.
达赖喇嘛也比不上我
Dalai Lama's got nothing on me.
O64  就是
O-64, as in,
"哦  又是64"
"Oh, to be 64 again!"
O64
O-64.
好吧
All right.
下一个号码是  N32
Next up...we got...N-32.
南希·里根的首字母哦
"N" As in "Nancy...Reagan,"
时髦的第一夫人
A first lady with a lot of style.
有人看过《海军悍妇》吗
Anybody else seen "Hellcats of the Navy"?
1957年电影  由里根夫妇主演
好吧  还是没人赢吗
All right. No winners yet?
好吧  现在是
Okay, here's...
B2  就是B2轰炸机
B-2, just like the B-2 bomber,
隐形机
The stealth --
说不定现在柯特兰空军基地就有一架起飞
There's probably one taking off over at Kirtland right now.
反正是隐形的  咱们也看不见
We would never know because it's stealthy.
还是没人赢吗  真的吗
Still no winners? No?
现在是
Here we have...
B4  又来个B打头的  怎么样
...B-4, another "B." How about that?
"不久之后  就会又有一名赢家"
As in, "Before too long, we're gonna have another winner."
还是没有吗  好吧
No? Nobody? Okay.
好吧
All right.
接下来是
And here comes...
咱们的老朋友B
Hey, it's our old friend "B."
B12
B-12.
B开头的...
"B," As in, uh...
"B," As in...
"背叛"
"Betrayal" --
本尼迪克特·阿诺德背叛了美国
Benedict Arnold betrayed the United States.
美国独立战争时期军官  后变节投靠英军
还是没有胜利者吗
Still no winners.
没有吗
No?
好的
Okay.
下一个
Here it is.
多巧啊
Oh, what are the odds?
连来四个B  真是...
Four B's in a row That's...
B7
B-7.
B开头的...
"B" As in...
B开头的...兄弟  兄弟
"B" As in..."brother" -- brother.
B7  七个兄弟七个新娘
B-7 -- "Seven brides for seven brothers."
我相信你们很多人都有兄弟
I'm sure a lot of you have brothers.
但肯定和我兄弟不一样
It's not like mine, though.
有人赢了吗
Any winners yet?
再...再看看  行吗
Take a -- take another look, okay?
我等着
I'll wait.
我要说的是...
All I'm gonna say is,
如果又是个B  那就出问题了
if it's another "B," could have a real problem here.
接下来
And...
又是一个B
Hey, it is another "B."
B5  开头的...
B-5, as in,
"用B造句真是让我快疯了"
"Boy, this 'b' thing is really starting to tick me off."
B打头的"战舰"  B打头的"波旁酒"
"B" As in "Battleship." "B" As in "Bourbon."
B打头的"伯利兹"  听说是个很美的地方
"B" As in "Belize" -- beautiful place, so I've heard.
我很想去那里
I would love to go there.
但咱们还是直面现实吧  那不可能
But, uh, let's face it -- that's never gonna happen.
咱们没人能离开这该死的荒漠
None of us is ever leaving this godforsaken wasteland.
不好意思
Sorry.
你们当没听到  咱们继续玩
Scratch that. Moving on.
这鬼地方到底怎么了
I mean, what is it with this place?
感觉像是在一个烤箱里
It's -- it's like living inside an easy-bake oven.
你们往窗外看看
I mean, look out that window.
外面简直就像
It's -- it's like a soulless,
乔治亚·欧姬芙描绘的毫无生气的地狱
radioactive Georgia O'Keeffe hellscape out there,
20世纪美国艺术家
爬满了珊瑚蛇和蝎子以及...
crawling with coral snakes and scorpions and...
你们没看过《隔山有眼》吗
You ever see the movie "The Hills Have Eyes"?
恐怖片  核辐射杀人狂魔的故事
够胆你就看
那简直就是个记录片
It's a documentary!
你的车突然抛锚了
God forbid your car breaks down --
你不得不下车步行
you have to walk 10 steps.
你的脑袋变成了
You got a melanoma the size of
一个菠萝那么大的黑瘤子
a pineapple where your head used to be.
你问我"为什么会这样"  为什么
And so you ask, "Why?" Why?
如果我感觉这么糟  为什么还待在这
If -- if that's how I feel, why do I live here?
是啊  为什么
Why?!
不好意思
Excuse me.
你还说不说数字了
Are you gonna read that number?
说  我这就告诉你
Yeah. I'm gonna read your number.
又是一个B
And it's another "B."
又是一个该死的B  当然是B
It's another frigging "B." Boy, of course.
为什么不是B呢
Why not? Why not?!
下一个数字是...
And the next number...
问个小问题
Uh, quick question --
谁知道"芝加哥天窗"是什么吗
who here knows what a Chicago Sunroof is?
请参见第三集  致使吉米被捕的"小把戏"
有人知道吗
Anybody?
你知道吗  不知道  好吧
You, sir? No? Okay.
讲个真事  我老家那边有个叫切特的人
True story -- uh, back home, uh, there was this guy named Chet.
他是个大混蛋
Now, Chet was a real asshole.
他可能欠我的钱
He might have owed me some money.
也可能睡了我老婆...
He might have slept with my wife...
然后我老婆就变成了我前妻
before she became my ex-wife.
细节不重要
The details don't matter.
总之  我被冤枉了
Suffice it to say, I was wronged.
那是一个夏日夜晚
All right, so, one summer evening,
我出去喝了几杯  一杯两杯或者三杯
I was out having a few drinks -- one or two, maybe three.
你们懂的
You get the picture?
猜我这时候看到谁了  切特
And, uh, who do I see? Chet.
他开车过来  把车并排停在了
He drove up, and he double-parked
冰雪皇后门口  然后进去买冰淇淋了
outside a Dairy Queen and went in to get some soft-serve.
切特开的车可以说明
Now, Chet drove -- and this will give you an idea
他是一个彻头彻尾的混蛋
of exactly what kind of a douchebag this guy was --
他开着一辆珍珠白宝马7系
drove a white pearlescent BMW 7 series
内饰也是白色皮革的
with white leather interior.
我看到了他的车
So, I saw that thing,
我突然灵机一动  像我之前说的
and I had -- I'd had a few, like I said.
我爬到了车顶
And, uh... I climbed up top,
可能...
and I may have...
对着天窗拉了泡屎
defecated, uh, through the sunroof.
我并不引以为豪
Not my finest hour -- I'll grant you that.
这就是"芝加哥天窗"的含义
But that's what a Chicago Sunroof is.
现在你们知道了  这是个真实的故事
Now you know. It's a real thing.
不是我编的  我也不是第一个做这种事的
I didn't make it up. I'm not the first person to do it.
它是有专门名字的
There's a name for it.
他想要一些冰淇淋  那我就给他一些冰淇淋
Guy wanted some soft-serve -- I gave him some soft-serve.
我根本不知道他的孩子坐在车后座上
I did not know that his children were in the backseat.
他那车窗不是透明的
There was a level of tint on the windows
至今我仍认为
that I'll maintain to this day
这在伊利诺伊州的车上是违法的
was not legal in an Illinois-licensed vehicle.
但不知怎么的  这变成了我的错
But somehow, that's on me, I guess.
谁会把车停在路边  不熄火
Who leaves two cub scouts in a double-parked car
还让两个孩子待在里面啊
with the engine running?!
拜托
Come on.
切特人脉很广
Now, Chet was connected, see?
在西塞罗混得人熟
Like, uh, Cicero connected.
通常情况  我会被指控故意损害他人财产
So, usually, I'd be looking at malicious mischief,
公共场所酗酒  妨碍社会治安  都有可能
public intoxication, disorderly conduct, maybe,
可是切特却让检察官指控我是个露阴癖
but he's got the D.A. saying indecent exposure,
把我说成是性侵犯
calling me a sex offender. What?
只是个小小的天窗恶作剧
One little Chicago Sunroof,
突然间我就跟查尔斯·曼森[杀人狂]一样了
and suddenly I'm Charles Manson?!
从那以后一切都失控了
And that's where it all went off the rails.
我一直在为此付出代价
I've been paying for it ever since.
这就是我为什么沦落到这
That's why I'm here!
我不
I don't...
你们猜怎么着
You know what?
这些东西你们想要就过来拿吧
Any of this stuff you want, come get it.
小猫笔记本  每人一本
Kitty-cat notebooks for everybody.
芝加哥  绿丝带出租车
要点儿啥
What can I get you?
老风格啤酒
Old style.
两瓶
Make it two.
好的
You got it.
-莫娜呢  -莫娜
- What happened to Merna? - Merna?
她很好
She's doing all right.
她是我继母
She's my stepmom.
她不常来了
She don't come in much anymore.
跟她说风流吉米向她问好
Tell her Slippin' Jimmy says hello.
"风流吉米"
Slippin' Jimmy?
她知道的
She'll know.
我会告诉她的
I'll tell her.
一共五块五
That'll be $5.50.
马可
Marco...
你这头帅气壮熊
You gorgeous hunk of a man...
你要让我等多久
...how long will you keep me waiting?
快醒醒  你个死胖子
Mnh! Wake up, you fat son of a bitch.
给你买了瓶酒
Bought you a beer.
吉米
Jimmy?
正是在下
In the flesh.
我还不够黑是吗
So, I'm not dark enough for you, huh?
不不  我只是说你肤色没黑
No, no. I'm just saying I don't see any color.
在沙漠里待了十年  你应该看起来像
I mean, 10 years in the desert, you should look like, uh,
《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》里的安东尼·奎恩才对
Anthony Quinn in "Lawrence of Arabia."
土耳其人  他们给了我一堆财宝
Turks -- they paid me a golden treasure!
-但我还是穷  -因为我是...
- Yet I am poor... - because I am a...
-人民的河流  -人民的河流
- river to my people! - ...river to my people!
我可是爱尔兰人
Well, hey, I'm irish, okay?
我可不待在太阳底下
I spend my time staying out of the sun.
说起脸色苍白的混蛋
Speaking of pale sons of bitches,
你哥哥怎么样了
how's your brother doing?
查克很好
Chuck's fine.
你还在给他工作吗
Still working for him?
有时候吧
Sometimes.
你呢  除了周三下午四点
What about you -- I mean, besides falling asleep on a bar
在酒吧睡觉以外还干嘛
at 4:00 on a Wednesday afternoon?
"密歇根湖竖管公司"
"Lake Michigan Standpipe"?
-那是什么  -我姐夫的公司
- What's that? - My brother-in-law owns the company.
等等  你结婚了
Wait. Hold it. You got married?
不不  我姐姐安吉的丈夫
No, no, no. My -- my -- my sister Angie's husband.
竖管是个什么东西
So, what the hell's a standpipe?
你知道的啊
Standpipe -- you know what a standpipe is.
-我不知道  -消防队来了
- I don't think so. - Fire department comes.
他们把水管的一端接到消防栓上
They stick one end of the hose on the hydrant.
另一端接到竖管上
The other end goes on the standpipe.
水从竖管中出来
The water goes out the standpipe,
经过喷头  然后灭火
through the sprinklers, and then douses the flames.
这是很重要的东西
It's important stuff.
这就是竖管吗
So, that's what a standpipe is, huh?
这只是干式竖管  还有湿式竖管
Well, it's a dry standpipe. There's also the wet standpipe.
有什么区别
What's the difference?
我不知道怎么跟外行人解释
I don't know i-if I could explain it to a layman.
不好意思  你妈妈还好吗
Excuse me. How's your mom?
她三年前就去世了
Oh, she passed away about three years ago.
真可惜  她是位了不起的女士
Ah. That's too bad. She was a great lady.
-是啊  -她是威斯康星州的  对吧
- Yeah. - From Wisconsin, right?
-对啊  -葬礼也是在那儿办的吗
- Yeah. - The funeral out there?
不  就在这儿办的
No, it was...here.
这里吗
Here?
是的  我们只在镇上呆了几天  所以...
Yeah, well, we were only in town for a few days, so...
你回来了怎么不找我
You were in town. You didn't look me up?
查克当时正在打一个大官司
Chuck was in the middle of a big case,
所以我们不能呆太久  所以...
and, uh, we couldn't stay around, so...
你们还要点别的吗
Can I get you guys anything else?
我不用了  你呢
I'm good. You want anything?
-不了  -给您的找零
- Nah. - Your change here, too.
好的
Uh, yeah, okay. Hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的短剑汽车还好吧
How's my Cutlass running?
我一直开着呢
Gets me around.
那可是经典款啊
Well, it's a classic.
只要车身稍微上点漆  简直帅呆了
Little bodywork, paint job -- really be something.
那你这次回来是做什么呢
So, what you gonna do while you're here?
我也不知道
I don't know.
看看风景吧
See the sights, you know,
去看台上看个球赛
Catch a cubbies game from the bleachers,
去亨利店里吃个热狗
Get a hot dog at Henry's.
对  对
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
正确
Correct.
我明天去见他们
I'm gonna see them tomorrow.
是的  他们俩
Yeah, both of them.
好的  再见
Okay. Okay, bye.
他是常客吗
Is he a regular?
不是
No.
你来买  我来卖
You're buying, I'm selling.
那好吧
All right, then.
就请你看一眼
All I'm asking is that you take a look.
对不起  伙计  没有冒犯你的意思
I'm sorry, buddy -- no offense.
我真的不感兴趣
I'm just -- you know, I'm not interested.
得了吧  伙计
Come on, man.
看一眼又不会怎么样
What's it gonna hurt to take a look?
只占用你两秒钟
It'll take you two seconds.
好吧
All right.
好吧  给我看看
All right. Show me what you got.
瞧
Boom.
好吧
Okay.
你看到了吗
Do you see it?
我看到一枚肯尼迪五十美分币
I see a Kennedy half-dollar.
他面朝哪里
Which way is he facing?
他面朝左
JFK's facing left.
正确
Exactly.
那么他应该面朝哪个方向呢
Hey, which way is he supposed to be facing?
右  他应该面朝右的
Right -- he's supposed to be facing right.
好吧  那么为什么这枚币上是朝左呢
Okay, so why -- why is this one facing left?
1963年11月22日
November 22, 1963 --
肯尼迪遇刺  对吧
Kennedy is assassinated, right?
举国哀恸
The whole nation goes into mourning.
人们开始把看到的每件东西都以他命名
They start naming everything in sight after him.
造币厂也想掺一脚
And the mint wants in on the act.
因此在六四年
So, in '64,
他们决定把林肯五十美分币
they decide to change the Lincoln half-dollar
改成肯尼迪五十美分币
into the Kennedy half-dollar.
当初设计时  肯尼迪是面朝右的
When they design it, they put Kennedy facing right,
即面朝东  和林肯的朝向一样
facing east, just the way they had Lincoln.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
东方象征着黎明
East symbolizes the dawn.
这也是为什么每座坟墓也是面朝东的  懂吗
It's why pretty much every grave everywhere faces east, you know?
好让逝者的灵魂面朝初升的太阳
So the spirit of the dead person faces the rising sun.
这是丧葬习俗
You know, it's a death thing. It's a burial thing.
然而丹佛造币厂有个技术人员
But there's one technician in the Denver Mint, right?
这个人  他相信肯尼迪政府的新疆界政策
And this guy -- he believed in, uh, the New Frontier --
光辉岁月  这些施政理念
Camelot, the whole deal.
肯尼迪任美国总统时华盛顿的繁荣景象
因此肯尼迪遇刺对他是个毁灭性打击
So, the assassination just destroyed him.
当他看到币上肯尼迪面朝东方
When he sees that coin with Kennedy facing east,
面朝美国的过去时  他被激怒了
facing the American past, pissed him off.
所以他特立独行
And so he went rogue.
在没有告诉任何人的情况下
Without telling anybody,
他把设计翻了个面
he flipped things around
好让肯尼迪面朝西方
so that Kennedy was facing west,
朝向新疆界  朝向未来
towards the new frontier, the future.
铸造了大约三千枚这样的错币之后
Now, the mint struck about 3,000 of these
造币厂才发现其中端倪
before they figured it out.
这名技术人员被抓
They canned the guy.
有大约一千枚错币进入市场流通
About 1,000 of them made it out into general circulation.
后来大部分被追回
They managed to get most of them back,
然后被熔毁  不过...
melt them down, but...
还是有...
there are still...
大概两百多枚在外流通
...200-plus floating around out there.
你说啥  我没听清
What's that? I didn't catch that.
我什么也没说
I didn't say anything.
你不介意吧  伙计
Do you mind, buddy?
我们正在聊些私事儿
We're having a private conversation here.
这枚品相不算最好
This one's not in perfect condition,
但市面上的价格
but on the open market,
我想它还是会值...  六到八百块
I'd say it's worth... 600 or 800 bucks.
八百块
$800?
是的  不过我实在手头紧
Yeah, but I'm hard up,
所以一百块便宜出了
So I'll take, uh, $100 for it.
你想让我出一百块买你的五十分硬币
You want me to give you $100 for a half-dollar.
我想让你出一百块  买价值八百块的硬币
I want you to give me $100 for an $800 coin.
算了吧  哥们
Yeah, I don't know, man. You know?
我先去方便一下  你再想想
I'm gonna go drain the snake. Think about it.
那货在耍我  对吧
This guy's playing me, right?
当然了
Definitely.
真是个王八蛋
Slick son of a bitch.
我看  我就应该...
You know, I should...
告诉你  我在沃巴什认识一个人
You know what? I know this guy on Wabash --
是个钱币商  我叔叔的朋友
Coin dealer, a friend of my uncle's.
乔伊  用用你的电话行吗
Hey, Joey, can I use your phone?
-就打给本地人  -别打太久
- Local call. - Keep it short.
好
Right on.
我找找号码
Let's see. Man.
我给他打个电话  如果他说这是个骗局
I'm gonna call this guy, and when he tells me this is a scam,
你知道我要干嘛吗  我要报警
You know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna call the cops
让那混蛋进局子
and get this scumbag thrown in the can.
你就是我的证人  行吗
You're my witness, okay?
还面朝西
Facing west.
放狗屁
My hairy ass.
你好啊
Hey. How you doing?
我是阿尔文  戴夫·坦纳的侄子
Yeah, it's Alvin, Dave Tanner's nephew.
是啊是啊
Yeah, mm-hmm.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
我要和你说件事  可不是开玩笑
Hey, this is gonna sound like the beginning of a bad joke,
我在酒吧里碰见个人
but, uh, I'm in this bar, and I've got this guy
满嘴跑火车
spinning this cock-and-bull story
想卖给我个五十分硬币
about this, uh, 50-cent piece he's trying to sell me.
他说什么肯尼迪的脸
He says, uh -- says Kennedy's supposed to be
本应该是朝西的
facing west or something.
没错
Yeah
这样啊
Yeah?
嗯
Yeah.
提示音响时为下午五时十一分
At the tone, the time will be 5:11 P.M.
没错  他说的就是丹佛
Yeah. That's what he said -- Denver.
天哪  你没开玩笑吧
Jesus. No kidding?
-提示音...  - 那个  我得挂了
- At the tone... - Well, listen, I got to go.
好吗  谢谢你
All right? Uh, thank you.
你可帮了我大忙
And I owe you one.
谢谢  乔伊
Thanks, Joey.
他怎么说的
So, what did he say?
这个嘛  他说  他也不太清楚
Yeah, you know, he -- he didn't really know much.
这样  给你五十块  我买你的硬币
I'll tell you what -- I'll give you $50 for it.
才五十  卖一百块我都不赚
$50? I'm taking a bath at $100.
好吧
A-all right. Okay.
你看  我这有六十四块
Look, I got... $64 right here.
这可是价值八百块的硬币
It's an $800 coin, okay?
怎么能六十四块就卖给你
I'm not gonna sell it to you for $64.
这样  你等着我  我马上拿一百块来
Okay, if you wait for me, I'll get you 100 bucks.
-也行吧  -好吧
- I don't know. - Okay.
哥们  我这儿有七十五块
Hey, buddy, I got 75 bucks right here.
对不起  一百块我才卖
I-I -- sorry. I need $100.
没人和你说话
Hey, slick, nobody's talking to you.
管好你自己的事就行了
Mind your own business, okay, come on?
那八十块现金呢
Cash money, $80.
你要是等等我  我等下给你一百一
Look, if you give me a chance, I'll be back with $110.
等多久
How long will that be?
我不知道  我得先去赶火车  再回来
I don't know. I got to catch a train, come back --
-一小时  最多一个半小时  -你知道吗
- Hour, hour and a half at the most. - Yeah, you know, this guy
-这人刚才还说要报警抓你  -我没说
- was getting ready to call the cops on you. - No, I was not.
什么  你怎么这样
What? Why would you do that?
这都是他胡编乱造的
That -- that -- now this guy is making shit up!
我这儿有一百一
Hey, I got $110 right here.
-就卖给你了  -不行不行
- Sold. - No! No, no, no, no, no, no.
人家给的可是现金
This guy's got the cash. Now...
-你不能这样  -拿好
- Don't do that. - Here, take care of that.
这可是有历史价值的
That's history right there.
-你怎么能这样  -怪你自己没钱吧
- Hey, you can't do that. - Hey, money talks.
游戏结束  你输了
You lost. It's over.
什么结束  你放什么狗屁
No, it's not over. No, that's crap.
你要去哪你
And where do you think you're going, huh?
哥们  别碰我
Hey, back off, dude.
你把硬币给我  我就放你走
Yeah, I'll back off when you give me the JFK back.
乔伊  快报警
Hey, Joey, call the cops.
这人抢了我的钱
This guy just tried to rip me off.
他才是骗子  我谁也没骗
Hey, this guy's a liar. I did not rip anybody off.
你怎么没骗
Yes, you did!
你敢回来  看我揍不死你
You come back in here, and your ass is grass!
我上头有人
I got friends, buddy!
记住了吗  你个死骗子
Do you hear me?! You double-dealing bastard!
我朋友一抓一大把
I got friends!
你真棒
You are so beautiful!
大家听着  下一杯酒我们请
Hey, everybody, next round's on us!
好  你在听我说吗
All right. Are you listening?
能保密吗
Can you keep a secret?
当然了  没问题
Yeah. Absolutely.
那人叫伊迪·阿巴西
Okay, his name is Idi Abbassi.
二十七岁
He's 27 years old.
是尼日利亚王子
He's a Nigerian prince, all right?
他的身价  少说也有四亿美元
He's worth, conservatively, $400 million.
出自于博尔赫斯的小说
《特隆  乌克巴尔  奥比斯·特蒂乌斯》
赤道乌克巴尔奥比斯国的独裁政权
The dictatorship of Equatorial Uqbar Orbis
诬告他  并将他扣押
is detaining him on trumped-up charges.
阿巴西的家人快急疯了
Now, the Abbassi family -- they're going crazy.
任何帮他们把儿子救出来的人  都能受重赏
They will reward whoever helps them get their boy back.
但问题是  银行冻结了他们的资产
The hitch is, the banks have frozen their......assets
我说的是爱尔兰的赛马马票
I'm talking Irish sweeps tickets,
满满一车都是
a whole trunk full of 'em.
就在芝加哥奥黑尔机场  被海关扣押
They're just sitting at O'Hare, impounded in customs.
我知道你想说"那又怎样"
Now, I know what you're saying, "So what?"
我本可以用它作抵押  但你要知道
I can leave this as security, but you got to understand --
这把小提琴就是我的命根  是价值连城的古董
this violin is my livelihood. It's a valuable antique.
为什么说它不是你的
What do you mean it doesn't belong to you?
我出九百块买你这个  现金支付
I'll pay you 900 bucks for this -- cash on the barrel.
我不想卖  我可不想离开我的琴
I don't know. I hate to part with it.
它在我家已经很多年了
It's been in my family for years.
你会保密的  对吧
You can keep a secret, right?
当然了
Yeah, absolutely.
不过关键是得有个好名头
But the point is, you need a good front,
这样才能获得最大收益
so you're gonna have the most return on your dollars.
但我知道一个海关人员...
But I know this customs officer...
那些钱  做个很好的投资
...that money, then make it an investment.
如果价格合理
...if the price is right.
我只关心投资  只关心收益
And I'm all about investments, all about what's coming next.
小子  帮我把我老婆的车
Hey, kid, help me get my wife's car
从那治安混乱的街区里开出来
out of this bad neighborhood.
先生  先生  能帮我个忙吗
Sir, sir, could you help me?
告诉我  这些是今天的数字吗
Tell me -- are these today's numbers?
没有一个是完全合法的
Now, none of this was strictly legal,
-进口税高得吓人...  -试试吧
- and the import taxes would have been a killer... - have at it.
所以他必须想办法让钱神不知鬼不觉地
...so he had to find a way to get the money into the country
流入国内
without anyone knowing about it.
他在钞票上涂了一层黑色的东西...
He coated the cash with this black stuff --
威克创胶
Vectrol paste.
只有用一种特殊的化学药品才能将其除掉
And the only way to get it off is with a special chemical.
虽然价格不菲  但利润呢
It's not cheap, but the upside?
利润相当可观
The upside is huge.
你能替我保守秘密吗
Can you keep a secret?
就是《与狼共舞》里的那个人
You know, the guy in "Dances with Wolves"?
一个像你这样的人  有钱
A guy like you, who's got some money,
有钱拿来挥霍...
who's got some money to throw around...
我知道你想说"谁在乎呢"
Now, I know what you're saying -- "Who cares?"
不管哪一方得利  我们都会分一杯羹
No matter which one wins, we're gonna get a piece.
他嗜赌如命
He's got a gambling problem.
你从中获利  没有人会来找你的麻烦
Nobody can ever come after you, but you get the profit.
-价格很合理  -对你来讲是双赢
- The price is right. - It's a win-win for you.
对其他人都是双输的局面
It's a lose-lose for everybody else.
告诉他你有张十四
You want to tell the guy you've got a 14.
-他去查...  -所以我们要合伙
- He checks... - That's why we're getting a consortium together.
-发现他...  -不只你一个人
- ...realizes he's... - it's not gonna just be you.
只是其中的一部分
It's gonna be a piece of the pie.
但我保证你会获得巨大的利益
But you're gonna own a full mountain range, guaranteed.
-你能保守  -秘密吗
- Can you keep... - ...a secret?
因为我真的...
'cause I really...
真的不该...
...really shouldn't...
不该告诉你这些
...shouldn't be telling you this.
《与狼共舞》主演
你不是凯文·科斯特纳
You are not Kevin Costner.
昨晚我是
I was last night.
天呐
Jesus.
混蛋
Asshole.
你开什么玩笑
I mean, seriously?
老天
Oh, my god.
-露西安  露西安  -干什么
- Lucianne?! Lucianne! - What?
-他不是凯文·科斯特纳  -什么
- He's not Kevin Costner. - What?!
那他是谁
Well, who's this guy?
也不是凯文·科斯特纳的经纪人
Uh, not Kevin Costner's manager.
来吧  我们走
Oh, come on. Come on. Let's go.
等等  我要把裙子先穿上
Uh, hang on. Got to get my dress on.
走吧  快离开这破地方
Come on. Get the hell out of this dump.
你确定他不是经纪人吗
So, are you sure he's not a manager?
是的  露西  我确定
Yes, Luci, I am sure.
但他说会把他的卡给我用的
But he said he was gonna give me his card.
你觉得这里像是经纪人住的地方吗
Does this look like a manager's place?
-也许吧  -二位对含羞草鸡尾酒感兴趣吗
- Maybe. - Can I interest you ladies in some mimosas?
至少留下来把衣服穿好啊
At least stick around long enough to get dressed.
去死吧
Screw you.
如果你建了  我就会来
If you build it, I will come.
语出电影《梦幻之地》
露西  快走
Lucy, come on.
好的  再见
Okay. Bye.
快走
Come on.
那扇门很难开
That door sticks.
-我知道  我能打开  -好吧
- Yeah, okay. I got it. - Okay.
-快走  -好的
- Go. Go. - Okay.
你有十五条留言
You have 15 messages.
我是葛丽塔·穆勒
This is Greta Muller.
我想知道我的遗嘱是否...
I wanted to check to see if my wi--
我的名字叫加里·阿尔伯特·阿诺德
My name's Gary Albert Arnold.
我想跟你探讨一下...
I'd like to discuss making a --
你好  麦吉尔先生
Hi, Mr. McGill.
我代表我母亲给你打电话
I'm calling on behalf of my mother.
她在生活协助中心...
She's in assisted living, and --
麦吉尔先生  我是曼尼·霍林格
Uh, yes, Mr. McGill, this is Manny Hollinger...again.
我真不想...
Uh, I hate to --
你好  麦吉尔先生...
Hey, Mr. McGill...
今天打算干什么  伙计
So, what's it gonna be today, pal?
我已经做好一切准备了
I'm up for anything and everything.
马可  很抱歉  我要回去了
Marco, I'm sorry. I got to go back.
什么
What?
我过得很愉快  很感谢你的款待
Uh, it's been great, and I appreciate your hospitality,
但一周已经足够了
but a week's gonna have to do it.
我要回家了
I got to go home.
可我已经请病假了
I already called in sick.
老兄  这里才是你的家  你不喜欢那里
Come on, man. This is home. Y-you hate it out there.
你回去又能干什么呢
What do you got to go back to?
我的委托人
My clients.
委托人
Clients.
怎么  你是...  你是小白脸吗
What -- what are you -- like a gigolo or something?
马可...
Uh, Marco...
我是律师
...I'm a lawyer.
什么
What?
我发誓
Honest to god.
我专攻老年法  就是遗嘱和财产相关事宜
I do Elder law, which is like wills and estates.
所以你欺骗那些老年人吗
So you're ripping off old people?
不  我没有欺骗老年人
No, I'm not ripping off old people.
我没欺骗任何人
I'm not ripping off anybody.
老天呐  风流吉米是律师
Holy crap. Slippin' Jimmy's a lawyer?
怪不得你要回去
No wonder you want to go back.
你一定是沙漠之王
I mean, you got to be king of the desert,
开白色卡迪拉克招摇过市  赚大钱
driving around town in a white caddy, making bank.
我没有赚大钱
I'm not making bank.
只是勉强糊口  差不多吧
I'm making a living, more or less.
糊口
A living?
恕我直言
All due respect,
你是律师  却没有赚大钱
you're a lawyer and you're not making bank,
那你一定是方式有问题
you're doing it wrong.
我在开拓市场  要花费些时间
Well, I'm building something. Takes time.
想开拓市场的话  就在这里开拓吧
Well, you're gonna build something, build it out here.
在芝加哥当律师很赚钱  我保证
I mean, lawyers in Chicago make plenty -- I assure you.
我不知道怎么跟你说  马可
Yeah, I don't know what to tell you, Marco. I --
查克在阿尔布开克
Chuck's in Albuquerque.
再恕我直言  查克是个自大的混蛋
Again, all due respect -- Chuck's a stuck-up douchebag.
我不想太直白  但他根本不喜欢你
I hate to break it to you, but he doesn't even like you.
他是我哥
He's my brother.
好吧
Okay.
我懂  毕竟是家人
I-I get it -- family.
你得回去  但...
You got to go back. But...
还记得这个吗
...remember this?
劳力士表
The Rolex thing. What--
把这些表卖给我们的人怎么了
Whatever happened to the guy who used to sell us those?
金康  他被驱逐出境了
Jin Kang? He got deported.
这是最后一块  我们干吧
This is the last one. I say we go for it.
-不行  -干吧
- No. - Oh, come on.
上次我们赚了多少  六百美元
Last time, we did what? $600?
我们趁热打铁  轻轻松松卖上千
The hot streak we're on, I bet we break a grand, easy.
我可以借你些现金
I could lend you some cash.
我不需要你的钱  吉米
I don't need the money, Jimmy.
我要干活儿
I need this.
来吧  你很乐意帮别人立遗嘱
Come on. You say you're happy doing wills or whatever,
说真的  那很不错
good for you, man, seriously.
但我得告诉你
But I got to tell you --
竖管公司赚的钱不够我花  兄弟
Standpipes ain't cutting it for me, man.
我一无所有  吉米
I got nothing, Jimmy.
听我一次
Give me this.
听我的  兄弟
Give me this, man.
我做不到
I can't do it.
跟我干吧
Come on. Give me this.
-马可  -来吧
- Marco. - Give me this.
-来吧  -兄弟  听我说
- Come on. Come on. - Buddy, listen to me.
我在听  来吧
I'm listening. Come on.
就这最后一次
Just one last time.
-来吧  -我不会被你催眠
- Come on. - I'm not being hypnotized.
-不会吗  最后一次  -不行
- No? Okay. Come on, one more time. - I can't do it.
就最后一次
Just one more -- one more.
-听我说  -听你说了
- Hey, listen to me. - Just listen to you.
我在听  来吧
Yeah, I'm listening. Come on.
声音从腹部出来  兄弟
It's got to come from the gut, man.
-没错  -没错
- Yeah. - Yeah.
太疯狂了
Oh, that's crazy.
就像一头狼  你来
Just like a wolf. Go ahead.
不  再深一点
No, deeper, deeper.
没错  每当感到快乐无比时
Yeah, and you do that right at the moment of,
就这么嚎
you know, pure joy...
-没错  -快感会增强到...
- Yeah. - ...and it will escalate it 10...
十倍
...10 times.
这种东西
There's something,
-史前就有了  -你看
- it's prehistoric. - Hey, hey. Look.
五十  两百  四百
$50, $200, $400.
-这是谁的  -不知道
- Whose is it? - I don't know.
这里应该有一千块
There's got to be 1,000 bucks in here.
肯定有人...
Somebody must have...
靠
Oh, damn.
他还...
Is he, uh...
不知道
I don't know.
兄弟  听得到吗
Hey, buddy, you with us?
这家伙喝多了吧
Look, the guy's just had too many.
我们走吧  你想把钱分了吗
I say we move on. You want to split this?
马可  你没事吧
Marco, you okay?
马可
Marco?
什么  你认识这人
What -- do you know this guy?
快报警
Hey, call 911.
Call 911!
叫救护车
I need an ambulance.
我朋友犯心脏病了
My friend's having a heart attack.
在一条巷子里
We're in an alley,
拉塞尔和薛莫街的东南边
Uh, Southeast of LaSalle and Shermer.
我不知道
No, I-I don't know.
我找到他时就这样了
He was like this when I found him.
别挂
Hey, hold --
马可  马可  能听到吗
Marco, Marco, you with me?
-能听到吗  -我搞砸了
- You with me? - I screwed up.
不  你很棒  兄弟
No, you did -- you did good, buddy.
坚持住  行吗  他们在路上了
Just hold on, all right? They're on their way.
马上就过来
They'll be here in a minute.
吉米  你知道吗
Jimmy, you know what?
别说话  省口气吧
Just s-save your breath, okay?
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
这是我人生最快乐的一周
This was the greatest week of my life.
坚持住
Hang in there!
醒醒  兄弟
Hey, wake up, man!
快醒醒  马可
Come on! Marco, buddy!
救命啊
Help!
有人吗
Anybody!
马可
Marco!
吉米
Hey, jimmy.
兄弟
Oh, hey, bud.
能给根烟吗
Can I bum one?
这是他的吗
Is that his?
没错  他妈给我的
Yeah. His mom gave it to me.
就说很眼熟
Thought it looked familiar.
觉得今天该戴着
I figured I'd wear it today,
但不太确定
but I don't know.
我不喜欢大戒指  所以...
I'm not a big ring guy, so...
还能值几个钱呢
Still. Could be worth a couple of bucks.
得进去了
Better head back.
里头见
See you inside.
是弗瑞斯·巴勒吗
Is this Ferris Bueller?
《春天不是读书天》中的主角逃学生
你说
Speaking.
没想打扰你的假期
I don't want to interrupt your big day off.
我就问问  准备干嘛呀
Just checking in. What are you up to?
把这地方烧了
You know, burning down the place.
就知道你会这样
I wouldn't expect any less.
不管怎样  你现在还生气吗
So, whatever it was, did you get it out of your system?
不生气了
Yep, all gone.
很好  我想告诉你一些进展
Good. I want to run something by you.
矶鹞渡一案  哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所接不下
The Sandpiper case -- it's getting too big for HHM.
霍华德决定和另一家公司合作
Howard's decided to partner with another firm.
戴维斯梅因律所  你听说过他们吗
Davis and Main. You heard of them?
-当然  在圣达菲  -没错
- Sure, up in Santa Fe. - Right.
他们也听说过你  并且很感兴趣
Well, they've heard of you, too, and they're interested.
他们想给你个面试机会
They want to make you an offer contingent on an interview.
他们考虑给你合伙人机会
They've got a partner-track position in mind.
等下  什么
Wait. What?
合伙人机会  你是什么意思
Partner track? What are you talking about?
我是说在圣达菲有一间
I'm talking about there's an office in Santa Fe
写有你名字的办公室  或是可能有
with your name on it, or there could be,
你可以接自己的案子
and you'd be working on your case.
我
I -- well, I --
我不...
I don't even, uh...
查克不会同意的
Chuck wouldn't like it.
查克管不着
Chuck has no say in this.
你不是为他工作
You wouldn't be working for HHM,
查克不能左右戴维斯梅因律所
and Chuck can't tell Davis and Main who to hire.
为什么是我
Why me?
这是为了扣税还是搞慈善啊
Is this like a tax write-off or a charity thing?
目的是什么
What's the angle, huh?
吉米  我们一直在跟你的委托人联系
Jimmy, we've been talking to your clients,
矶鹞渡的那些老人
the Sandpiper residents,
他们一有机会就会问到你
and they ask about you every chance they get.
我不知道怎么回事  但他们很喜欢你
I don't know what it is, but you have a way with them.
老人都爱我
Old people love me.
那就这么说定了
So...sounds good?
金  我无法想象你为此做了多少努力
Kim, I can't imagine what you did to make this happen.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我也没做  太多
I didn't do anything... much.
不管你信不信  霍华德也为此做出了努力
And believe it or not, Howard's been pushing this, too.
老好人霍华德啊
Good, old Howard.
听着  周四上午十一点
Listen, we're gonna be down in Judge Murray's court
我们会在默里法官的法庭
on Thursday at 11:00.
戴维斯梅因律所的人也会在那儿
The Davis and Main people will be there.
那时候见他们再好不过了
It'd be the perfect chance for you to meet them.
周四上午十一点  好的  我准时到
Thursday at 11:00. All right, I'll be there.
真的谢谢你  金
Thanks, Kim, really.
到时见
I'll see you then.
所有原件都需复印并归档
All the originals need to be copied and filed.
我在盒子上写了  "复印和归档"
See, I've written right here on the box -- "Copy and file."
就是为了表达清楚
That's to make it as clear as possible.
明白了  麦吉尔先生  还有什么需要吗
Got it, Mr. McGill. Anything else?
关于食品方面
Well, on the grocery front,
这次几乎都买对了
almost everything was right this time.
-太好了  -"几乎"
- Great. - Almost.
只是件小事  但按我的口味
Um, it's a small thing, but to my taste,
澳洲青苹果有点儿太酸了
the, uh, Granny Smith apples are a bit too tart.
-你说的是那些绿色的对吗  -是的
- Those are the green ones, right? - Right.
我喜欢红色的那些  但不是红蛇果
I prefer the red ones, but not Red Delicious.
那些基本上没什么味道
Those are generally tasteless.
富士苹果应该上市了
Fujis should be in season.
这不是什么大事  但是
It's not a major issue, but...
明白了  富士苹果
Yeah. Fuji apples.
没问题
Okay.
我还想喝豆奶
Oh, and I'd like to try soy milk,
所以可以买半加仑
so maybe a half gallon of that.
没问题
You got it.
谢谢  欧内斯托
Well, thank you, Ernesto.
非常感谢你能注意细节
I appreciate your attention to detail.
你不需要把这些都写下来吗
Do you need to write any of this down?
写下来更好
'Cause it's okay if you do.
到时记得住
You know, just to be sure.
富士苹果
So, Fuji apples.
你好  欧尼
Hey, Ernie.
最近怎么样  伙计
How you doing, man?
还不错
Good, good.
霍华德让你来照顾查克啊
So, Howard's got you looking after Chuck, huh?
是啊  能多挣些
Yeah. It's a few extra bucks, you know?
他怎么样
How's he doing?
还可以  老样子
Seems okay, like usual.
本来咱可以去喝一杯的
I'd say we could grab a beer,
但他们等着我把文件带回公司
but they're waiting on all that paperwork back at the office --
你懂的
You know how it is.
可不是么
Don't I, though?
回头见  吉米
See you, Jimmy.
回头见  欧尼
Uh, see you 'round, Ernie.
你以前跟他打过交道吗
You done business with him before?
好的
Right.
我会去的
Yeah. I'll be there.
戴维斯梅因  麦吉尔
Davis and Main and McGill.
很高兴见到你们
Great to meet you.
很高兴见到你们  先生们
Nice to meet you, gentlemen.
见到你们真是太好了
It's good to meet you.
好
Nice...
挺快啊
Well, that was quick.
-不收费  -帮我想想
- No charge. - Help me out here.
我是在做梦  还是我办公桌上真的有
Did I dream it, or did I have $1,600,000
一百六十万美元现金
on my desk in cash?
闭上眼睛之后我还是能看到
When I close my eyes, I can still see it.
就好像我一直看着太阳
It's burned into my retinas
灼烧着我的视网膜
like I was staring into the sun.
地球上没人知道我们有这钱
No one on god's green earth knew we had it.
我们可以五五分成
We could have split it 50/50.
我们本可以每人带八十万美金回家  不用交税
We could have gone home with $800,000 each, tax-free.
你想说什么
Your point being?
我们为什么没那么干  什么阻止了我们
Why didn't we? What stopped us?
我记得你说  要做对的事
I remember you saying something about doing the right thing.
我都不知道那是什么意思
I don't even know what that means.
你想知道我为什么没拿那钱吗
You want to know why I didn't take that money?
你是在问这个吗
Is that what you're asking?
没错  我是想问那个问题
Yeah, that's what I'm asking.
对我个人来说  别人雇我干活
Me, personally -- I was hired to do a job.
我干完了  就结束了
I did it. That's as far as it goes.
是啊  我知道是什么阻止了我
Yeah. Well, I know what stopped me.
听好了  它再也不会阻止我了
And you know what? It's never stopping me again.